Guide to the Peter Megargee Brown Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Peter Megargee Brown papers
1952-1988
MS 1782
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
60
(102 boxes)
The collection contains bound volumes of material relating to the professional and personal activities of Peter Megargee Brown, a lawyer and author.
Brown, Peter Megargee
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Peter Megargee Brown, 2007.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Biographical / Historical
Peter Megargee Brown was born in Cleveland, Ohio, on March 15, 1922. Brown attended Yale from 1940 to 1943 and was active in the Yale Record, Yale Political Union, and athletic activities. After his induction into the Army in 1943, he received a Bachelor of Arts degree in 1944. In 1946, Brown entered Yale Law School and earned his Juris Doctorate degree in 1948. He was a special assistant to the New York State Attorney General and senior counsel to the New York State Crime Commission from 1952 to 1953 under John Marshall Harlan. Brown then served as assistant United States attorney in charge of the Federal Waterfront Prosecution from 1953 to 1956 under Judge J. Edward Lumbard.
In 1956, he began his twenty-six year career at the firm of Cadwalader, Wickersham & Taft and quickly rose to become the head of the litigation and ethics committee. Brown and his law partner, Whitney North Seymour, left in 1982 to form Brown & Seymour. The firm continued until the retirement of North in 1996; thereafter, Brown maintained a solo practice until his retirement in 2004.
Brown is the author of The Art of Questioning, Thirty Maxims of Cross-Examination, and Rascals: The Selling of the American Legal Profession, as well as several other non-legal titles.
Scope and Contents
The collection contains bound volumes of material relating to the professional and personal activities of Peter Megargee Brown, a lawyer and author.
Arrangement
Arranged generally by the activities in the creator's life: legal activities in rough chronological order, personal activities, and the collected writings of others.
Law -- United States; Lawyers -- United States; Brown, Peter Megargee
- General Legal Events
  Scope and Contents
  These volumes consist of printed materials relating to quasi-judicial activities.
  - Reports of New York State Crime Commission, 1953-1954 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - The Anti-Racketeering Act, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Crime in New York State, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Reports of New York State Commission on Investigation, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - 175th anniversary of the adoption of the United States Constitution, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - History of the United States District Court for the Southern District of New York, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - History of the United States District Court for the Eastern District of New York to Commemorate and to Celebrate a Centennium, 1865-1965 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - New York State Constitutional Convention Report, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Ten Reasons Why the Grand Jury In New York Should Be Retained and Strengthened-June 1967 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Opening of the Courts of Justice, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Resolutions of the Bar of the Supreme Court to be Presented to the Court at the Memorial Proceeding for Justice John M. Harlan, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Memorial Service for the Honorable Walter Bruchhausen, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Lumbard Association-25th Anniversary Dinner, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Joint Bar Committee Exoneration of Honorable Arnold G. Fraiman, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Reception and Dinner Honoring Chief Judge Irving R. Kaufman, Vols. I-II, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Additional material (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Report of the United States Attorney for the Southern District of New York, March 1, 1980-June 30, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - In Memoriam for Honorable Sylvester J. Ryan, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Tributes from the Celebration of the Life and Service of Francis Taylor Pearsons Plimpton, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - In Memoriam for Circuit Judge Walter R. Mansfield and Magistrate Edward M. Conan, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Honorable Malcolm Baldrige Memorials, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Judge Edward Weinfeld Memorial Service, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Significant Legal Events
  These bound volumes document the meeting of the American Bar Association in 1971 and 1976.
  - American Bar Association Meeting - London, England, 1971 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - American Bar Association Annual Meeting-Atlanta, Georgia, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Second Circuit Judicial Conference
    These bound volumes document the activities of the Second Circuit Judicial Conference from 1964 to 1986.
    - Second Circuit Judicial Conference-Notes and Letters, 1964-1968 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Second Circuit Judicial Conference-Equinox, 1969 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Second Circuit Judicial Conference-Whiteface, 1970 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Second Circuit Judicial Conference-Equinox, 1970 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Second Circuit Judicial Conference-Buck Hill Falls, 1974 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Second Circuit Judicial Conference-Buck Hill Falls, 1975 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Remarks of the Honorable Harold R. Medina, 1975 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Second Circuit Judicial Conference-Buck Hill Falls, 1976 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - The Singular Achievement of the Second Circuit, 1978 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Second Circuit Judicial Conference-Buck Hill Falls, May 1978-Medina Speech "The Rights, Privileges, and Power of the Press", 1979 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Second Circuit Judicial Conference-Buck Hill Falls, 1981 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Second Circuit Judicial Conference-Hartford, 1984 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Second Circuit Judicial Conference-Lake George, 1986 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Cadwalader, Wickersham & Taft
  - One Hundred and Seventy-Fifth Anniversary of Cadwalader, Wickersham and Taft, 1792-1967 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - One Hundred and Eighty-Fourth Anniversary of Cadwalader, Wickersham and Taft, 1792-1976 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - One Hundred and Eighty-Fifth Anniversary of Cadwalader, Wickersham and Taft, 1792-1977 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - One Hundred and Eighty-Sixth Anniversary of Cadwalader, Wickersham and Taft, 1792-1978 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Cadwalader, Wickersham and Taft firm meeting, March 8, 1980 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - The Labellum News, Vols. 3 and 4, 1958-1959 (Box 12, Folder 1-2)
  - The Labellum News, Vols.6-7, 1961-1962 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Quiet Revolution in The American Law Profession: Remarks before the Commission on Professionalism of the American Bar Association ( Fordham Urban Law Journal ), 1985-1986 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Is The Law Profession In Decline? (Ohio State Bar Association Report), 1983 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Raise a Cadre for Civilization- Georgetown Journal of Legal Ethics, 1988 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Keynote Speech-Massachusetts Statewide Legal Conference, April 30, 1988 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Troubles of Lawyers-Address at Ohio State Bar Association Annual Meeting-May 19, 1984 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - The Quiet Revolution In The American Law Profession-Articles 1983-1985, Vol. I (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Changing Nature of the Practice of Law-1984 Federal Bar Council-Puerto Rico Bench and Bar Conference (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Notes on the Decline of the Law Profession-Profession or Business?, 1984 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Decline of Lawyers' Professional Independence (New York State Bar Journal), Nov. 1983 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Decline of The American Law Profession-Spread of the Idea, Vols. I-III, 1984-1986 (Box 15, Folder 1-3)
  - Decline of The American Law Profession-Spread of the Idea, Vols. IV-V, 1985-1986 (Box 16, Folder 1-2)
- Specific Legal Cases
  These volumes contain legal documents from cases in which Peter Megargee Brown was counsel for one of the parties or cases in which he was interested.
  - United States v. Henry Gregory Varlick, Samuel Kavalauskas and David Bernard Roche, Defendants-Appellants and James Thomas Moock, Clifford Carter and Lawrence Wagner, Defendants, Vols. I-II, 1955 (Box 17, Folder 1-2)
  - United States v. Antonio Farina and United States v. Orlando Delli Paoli, 1954 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - United States v. Orlando Delli Paoli and United States v. Philip Albanese and Rosario Albanese, 1954 (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - United States v. Orlando Delli Paoli, 1955 (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - United States v. Philip Albanese and Rosario Albanese-Trial Record
    - Volume I, 1954 (Box 19, Folder 2)
    - Volume II (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - Volume III (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Ronald E. Gates v. P. F. Collier, Inc.-Appeal to Ninth Circuit, 1966 (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - Ronald E. Gates v. P. F. Collier-Supreme Court Petition and Brief, 1966 (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Ronald E. Gates v. P. F. Collier-Petition for Rehearing, 1966 (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - Ronald E. Gates v. P. F. Collier-Appendix D, 1966 (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - Ronald E. Gates v. P. F. Collier- Trial Record Vol. I, 1966 (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Ronald E. Gates v. P. F. Collier- Trial Record Vol. II-III, 1966 (Box 23, Folder 1-2)
  - Ronald E. Gates v. P. F. Collier- Trial Record Vol. IV, 1966 (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - People of the State of New York v. Sidney Street, 1967 (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - Sidney Street v. People of the State of New York-Brief and Appendix of Appellant, 1967 (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - Sidney Street v. People of the State of New York-Brief for Appellees, 1968 (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - People of the State of New York v. Sidney Street, 1967 (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - United States Law article re: Sidney Street v. State of New York, 1969 (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - Frank L. Lazarus v. The Bowery Savings Bank-Trial Record, Undated (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - Frank L. Lazarus v. The Bowery Savings Bank-Appeal, 1963 (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - Frank L. Lazarus v. The Bowery Savings Bank-Briefs ands Records, Undated (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - United States of America v. Herbert A. Ellenbogen, 1965 (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - Mccloy Report on Gulf Oil Corporation, Dec. 1975 (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - Charles Oakes Ames v. Shirley Foerderer Ames, 1983 (Box 26, Folder 4)
  - Hughes Tool Company et. al. v. Trans World Airlines, Inc., 1971 (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - Forty-Seventh-Fifth Co., v. Bretano's Inc.-Trial Memorandum, 1970 (Box 27, Folder 2)
  - Forty-Seventh-Fifth Co., v. Bretano's Inc.-Trial Transcript, 1970 (Box 27, Folder 3)
  - Vanity Fair Mills, Inc. v. The Eaton Co. Ltd., 1956 (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - Xerox v. International Business Machines Corporation-patent cases, 1969 (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - Xerox Corporation v. Nashua et al v. Radio Corporation of America-Interpleader, 1970 (Box 29, Folder 2)
  - Xerox Corporation v. Nashua et al v. Radio Corporation of America-Scope of interrogatories, 1965 (Box 29, Folder 3)
  - Lawrence Cantor v. The Detroit Edison Company, 1975 (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - Amicus Curiae-Grand Jury Secrecy, 1970 (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - In The Matter of The Hawaii Corporation, 1983 (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - George P. K. Ching v. Raoul Pujol and Banque de Paris et des Pays-Bas, 1982 (Box 30, Folder 4-5)
  - Pemati, Inc., and Penn Plaza Venture v. Bowery Savings Bank, 1973 (Box 31, Folder 1)
  - Pemati, Inc., and Penn Plaza Venture v. Bowery Savings Bank--Trial Briefs, 1973 (Box 32, Folder 1)
  - Joseph Demone v. Town Paper Corp. and The Macmillan Co., 1961 (Box 32, Folder 2)
  - Elliott F. Cavellier v. Mary Helen Cavellier, 1956 (Box 33, Folder 1)
  - Thelma C. Sherrer, et al. v. Robert B. Hodes, et al., 1980 (Box 33, Folder 2)
  - Holiday Inns. Inc. v. Aetna Insurance Company-Trial Memorandum, 1985 (Box 34, Folder 1)
  - Holiday Inns. Inc. v. Aetna Insurance Company--Summary Judgement, 1985 (Box 34, Folder 2)
  - Holiday Inns. Inc. v. Aetna Insurance Company--Beirut bombing--Opinion and Order, 1983-1985 (Box 34, Folder 3)
  - Joseph R. Clevenger v. New York Bank for Savings, 1965 (Box 34, Folder 4)
  - Albert B. Ashforth Inc. and Bert G. Gross & Co., Inc. v. The Equity Corporation and 101-103 Park Avenue, Inc., 1969 (Box 34, Folder 5)
  - The City of New York v. Comtel, Inc. and Bell Television, Inc. - Record, 1968 (Box 35, Folder 1)
  - The City of New York v. Comtel, Inc. and Bell Television, Inc. - Notice of Motion for Permission to Appeal and Affidavit and Brief In Support of Motion, 1969 (Box 35, Folder 2)
  - The City of New York v. Comtel, Inc. and Bell Television, Inc. - Affidavit and Brief In Opposition to Motion for Permission to Appeal, 1969 (Box 35, Folder 3)
  - The City of New York v. Comtel, Inc. and Bell Television, Inc. - Brief for Defendants-Respondents, 1969 (Box 35, Folder 4)
  - The City of New York v. Comtel, Inc. and Bell Television, Inc. - Reply Brief for Plaintiff-Appellant, 1969 (Box 35, Folder 5)
  - The City of New York v. Comtel, Inc. and Bell Television, Inc. -Cases Cited, 1969 (Box 36, Folder 1)
  - The City of New York v. Comtel, Inc. and Bell Television, Inc. - Plaintiff-Appellant Oral Argument, 1969 (Box 36, Folder 2)
  - Newark Motor Inn Corp. and Newark Motor Inn Company, v. Holiday Inns, Inc. and American Motor Inns, Inc., v. Arthur Fleck, Edwin Fleck, Samuel R. Patent and Peter Fitzpatrick-Motion for Summary Judgment by Holiday Inns Inc., 1979 (Box 36, Folder 3)
  - Newark Motor Inn Corp. and Newark Motor Inn Company, v. Holiday Inns, Inc. v. Arthur Fleck, Edwin Fleck, Samuel R. Patent and Peter Fitzpatrick-Memorandum of Law in Support of Motion for Summary Judgment by Holiday Inns, Inc., 1979 (Box 37, Folder 1)
  - Newark Motor Inn Corp. and Newark Motor Inn Company, v. Holiday Inns, Inc. and American Motor Inns, Inc., v. Arthur Fleck, Edwin Fleck, Samuel R. Patent and Peter Fitzpatrick-Motion on Order To Show Cause, 1979 (Box 37, Folder 2)
  - Hawk Industries, Inc. v. Bausch & Lomb-Cross Motion for Judgement on The Pleadings, 1972-1974 (Box 37, Folder 3)
  - New York Motel Enterprises v. Holiday Inns, Inc., General Data Corporation et. al. -Briefs and Affidavits-Motion To Dismiss and for Summary Judgement, 1979 (Box 38, Folder 1)
  - New York Motel Enterprises v. Holiday Inns, Inc., General Data Corporation et. al. -Briefs and Affidavits-Motion To Dismiss and for Summary Judgement -Basic Papers and Oral Arguments, 1979 (Box 38, Folder 2)
  - Grove Press, Inc. et. al. v. Central Intelligence Agency, et. al. and William E. Colby, James R. Schlesinger, James J. Angleton et. al.- Joint Appendix, 1979 (Box 39, Folder 1)
  - Grove Press, Inc. et. al. v. Central Intelligence Agency, et. al. and William E. Colby, James R. Schlesinger, James J. Angleton et. al.- Briefs, 1979 (Box 39, Folder 2)
  - Probate Proceeding Will of Gertrude Newcombe Steers-Trial Record on Appeal, 1965 (Box 40, Folder 1)
  - Probate Proceeding Will of Gertrude Newcombe Steers- Appeal To Appellant Division, 1966 (Box 40, Folder 2)
  - Probate Proceeding Will of Gertrude Newcombe Steers-Trial Record, 1966 (Box 41, Folder 1)
  - Eisen v. Post, 1957 (Box 41, Folder 2)
  - Salvatore Orlando v. Melvin Laird, Ind. and as Secretary of Defense; and Stanley R. Resor, Ind. and as Secretary of the Army (legality of Vietnam War), 1972 (Box 41, Folder 3)
  - P.F. Collier, Inc. v. Hanover Insurance Company-Trial Record, 1963-1969 (Box 42, Folder 1)
  - P.F. Collier, Inc. v. Hanover-Trial brief, 1969 (Box 42, Folder 2)
  - P. F. Collier, Inc. v. Hanover-Brief on appeal, Undated (Box 42, Folder 3)
  - Petition for Writ-Richard Helms et. al. v. Rodney D. Driver, 1978 (Box 43, Folder 1)
  - Last Argument of J.A. Swords-Driver v. Helms-!st Cir., 1978 (Box 43, Folder 2)
  - Petition for Certiorari and briefs-William E. Colby and Vernon A. Walters v. Rodney D. Driver, 1978-1979 (Box 43, Folder 3)
  - William H. Stafford, Jr., Stuart J. Carrouth and Claude Meadow v. John Biggs, et. al.-Petition for a Writ of Certiorari to U.S. Court of Appeals for the District of Columbia Circuit-Supreme Court-April 30, 1978 (Box 43, Folder 4)
  - Petition for Writ of Certiorari-William M. Stafford, Jr., Stuart J. Carrouth and Claude Meadow v. John Briggs et. al. (1977-1979) (Box 43, Folder 5)
  - William H. Stafford, Jr. et. al.-First Oral Arguments-April 24,1979-W.E. Colby and Vernon A. Walters, v. R.D. Driver et. al. (Box 44, Folder 1)
  - Stafford v. Briggs, Colby v. Driver- April 24, 1979-Articles on oral arguments (Box 44, Folder 2)
  - Stafford v. Briggs, Colby v. Driver-Second Round Argument-U.S. Supreme Court-Nov. 7, 1979 (Box 44, Folder 3)
  - Stafford v. Briggs, Colby v. Driver-Petition for Certiorari (Stafford) Appendices-Brief of the United States as amicus curiae, 1978 (Box 44, Folder 4)
  - Stafford v. Briggs-Supreme Court decision, 1980 (Box 44, Folder 5)
  - Superior Pet Products v. Geisler Pet Products, Undated (Box 45, Folder 1)
  - New York Air Brake Company v. Planet Corporation and Insurance Company of North America--Pre-Trial, 1963 (Box 45, Folder 2)
  - Securities and Exchange Commission v. National Student Marketing Corp.-Pretrial Brief, 1977 (Box 46, Folder 1)
  - International Business Machines Corporation v. David N. Edelstein, Chief Judge et. al.--Petition for Writ of Mandamus, 1975 (Box 46, Folder 2)
  - Report on Inquiry into Republican County Leader, Vincent F. Albano, Jr., 1968 (Box 46, Folder 3)
  - U.S. School of Music v. National Home Study Council, Inc.-Deposition of Dr. Derthick-Vols. I-II., 1970 (Box 47, Folder 1-2)
  - U.S. School of Music v. National Home Study Council- Deposition of Warren B. Smith Vols. I-II, 1970 (Box 47, Folder 3-4)
  - U.S. School of Music v. National Home Study Council- Deposition of Charles B. Marshall, 1970 (Box 48, Folder 1)
  - Gump Arbitration-Arthur Young & Company Arbitrator, 1971 (Box 48, Folder 2)
  - Riggs, Ferris & Gear v. Lillibridge-Appeal, 1962 (Box 49, Folder 1)
  - Riggs, Ferris & Gear v. Lillibridge-Record on Appeal, 1962 (Box 49, Folder 2)
  - Mallinckrodt Chemical Works v. Goldman, Sachs, & Co., Dun & Bradstreet, Inc. and Manufacturers Hanover Trust Company [fraud relating to Penn Central commercial paper]-Trial, 1975 (Box 50, Folder 1)
  - Mallinckrodt Chemical Works v. Goldman, Sachs, & Co., et. al.-Briefs, 1975 (Box 50, Folder 2)
  - United States v. Masiello and Stickel- (Racketeering), 1955 (Box 51, Folder 1)
  - United States v. Masiello and Stickel- (Racketeering)-Trial Record, 1955 (Box 51, Folder 2)
  - United States v. Masiello and Stickel-(Racketeering)-Briefs, 1955 (Box 52, Folder 1)
  - Dolan v. Indemnity Insurance Company of North America (accident policy), 1960-1962 (Box 52, Folder 2)
  - Application of St. Bartholomew's Church- Vols. I- II [proposed lease of church property], 1981-1982 (Box 53, Folder 1-2)
  - Cathedral Estates and Bank of New York v. Gustave L. Levy-Trial Testimony of Rudolph G. Merker and John Allen Brasfield, Jr. [Securities and common law fraud], Undated (Box 53, Folder 3)
  - Cathedral Estates and Bank of New York v. Goldman Sachs & Co. and Dun & Bradstreet-Trial Briefs [Securities and common law fraud], Undated (Box 54, Folder 1)
  - Cathedral Estates and Bank of New York v. Goldman Sachs & Co. and Dun & Bradstreet- Trial Record- Vol I. [Securities and common law fraud], Undated (Box 54, Folder 2)
  - Cathedral Estates and Bank of New York v. Goldman Sachs & Co. and Dun & Bradstreet- Trial Record- Vol. II [Securities and common law fraud], Undated (Box 55, Folder 1)
  - P.F. Collier, et al. v. Federal Trade Commission-Joint Appendix, Undated (Box 55, Folder 2)
  - Koreh v. Milhovan [Radio Free Europe libel suit], Undated (Box 56, Folder 1)
  - United States v. Chapman [stock fraud], Undated (Box 56, Folder 2)
  - Shahmoon Industries, Inc. v. Louis G. Imperato- Vols. I-II [fraud], Undated (Box 57, Folder 1-2)
  - Shahmoon Industries, Inc. v. Louis G. Imperato -Appeal, 1963 (Box 58, Folder 1)
  - West Tsusho, Co. Ltd. v. Prescott Bush & Company, Incorporated and Prescott S. Bush, Jr., Vol. I [Japanese mafia suit], Undated (Box 58, Folder 2)
  - West Tsusho, Co. Ltd. v. Prescott Bush & Company, Incorporated and Prescott S. Bush, Jr., Vols. II-III [Japanese mafia suit], Undated (Box 59, Folder 1-2)
  - Hearing on Application of Marina Associates and Harrah's Atlantic City, Inc. for casino licenses, 1987 (Box 60, Folder 1)
  - Report of New Jersey Department of Law and Public Safety-Division of Gaming Enforcement -Harrah's Marina Hotel casino and Teamsters Union Local 331 [1981], 1987 (Box 60, Folder 2)
  - Freeport Sulphur Company v. United States v. Soo Line Railroad Company, 1961-1962 (Box 61, Folder 1)
  - Union Savings National Bank v. James J. Saxton, Comptroller of the Currency and Tinker Bank, 1963 (Box 61, Folder 2)
  - William B. Camp, Comptroller and Tinker National Bank v. Union Savings Bank of Long Island, Island State Bank and Peoples National Bank of Long Island, Undated (Box 61, Folder 3)
  - Union Savings Bank of Patchogue, Island State Bank and Peoples National Bank of Patchogue vs. William B. Camp, Comptroller v. Tinker National Bank, 1967 (Box 62, Folder 1)
  - Tinker National Bank v. Union Savings Bank of Long Island, et. al. v. Union Savings Bank of Long Island, et. al.., 1967 (Box 62, Folder 2)
  - Union Savings Bank of Long Island, Island State Bank and Peoples National Bank of Long Island v. William B. Camp, Comptroller v. Tinker National Bank, 1967 (Box 62, Folder 3)
  - Kenrich Properties, Inc. v. City Title Insurance Co. [Title insurance policy], 1964 (Box 63, Folder 1-2)
  - Kenrich Properties, Inc. v. City Title Insurance Company- Briefs, Undated (Box 63, Folder 3)
  - Welch Foods Inc. v. Goldman Sachs & Co., Undated (Box 64, Folder 1)
  - Welch Foods Inc. v. Goldman Sachs & Co.-Openings, Summations, and Memorandums, 1974 (Box 64, Folder 2)
  - Assante v. The Sugar Tree Restaurant, et. al., Undated (Box 64, Folder 3)
  - Securities and Exchange Commission v. Bausch & Lomb Inc., Vols. I-III, 1972-1974 (Box 65, Folder 1-3)
  - In The Matter of Bausch & Lomb, Inc. [SEC Rule 10b-5], 1972 (Box 65, Folder 4)
  - In the Matter of Equity Funding Corporation of America-Memorandum of The Boston Company Institutional Investors, Inc. and John W. Bristol & Co., Inc., 1974 (Box 66, Folder 1)
  - In the Matter of Equity Funding Corporation of America- Submissions by Bristol and III to S.E.C., 1974-1975 (Box 66, Folder 2)
  - Securities and Exchange Commission- Administrative Proceedings to 1976 (Box 66, Folder 3)
  - Securities and Exchange Commission- Administrative Proceedings-In the Matter of Boston Institutional Investors Inc. et. al., 1976 (Box 66, Folder 4)
  - Securities and Exchange Commission v. The Boston Company Institutional Investors, Inc.-Testimony of John Bristol, Vol. I, 1977 (Box 66, Folder 5)
    - Additional material (Box 67, Folder 1)
  - The Boston Company Institutional Investors, et. al.-Additional Motion of John W. Bristol & Co. to Dismiss and Memorandum, 1977 (Box 67, Folder 2)
  - The Boston Company Institutional Investors, et. al.-Memorandum of John W. Bristol & Co. Inc. in Opposition to Motion to Conform Order for Proceedings to the Proof, 1977 (Box 67, Folder 3)
  - Securities and Exchange Commission-In The Matter of The Boston Company Institutional Investor, Inc. et. al.-Proposed Findings of Fact, Conclusions of Law and Memorandum in Support by United States, 1977 (Box 67, Folder 4)
  - Securities and Exchange Commission-In the matter of The Boston Company Institutional Investors, Inc. et. al.-Memorandum of John W. Bristol & Co., Inc. in Support of Proposed Findings of Fact and Conclusions of Law, 1978 (Box 67, Folder 5)
  - Securities and Exchange Commission-In the Matter of The Boston Company Institutional Investors, Inc. et. al.- Joint Memorandum in Support of Findings of Fact and Conclusions of Law, 1978 (Box 68, Folder 1)